lan Hatton

Front-end Developer

ian-hatton.com contact@ian-hatton.com

GitHub LinkedIn npm

A conscientious, forward-thinking Front-end Developer with over 10 years' experience.

My strengths range from a thorough understanding of JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Angular, CSS and HTML to a firm grasp of web standards, typography and graphic design principles.

I'm in my element whether I'm creating solutions to complex technical issues, building bespoke designs, writing tests or working with UX teams to ensure that their visions are realised to their full potential.

Objective

To apply my skills and knowledge as a Senior Front-end Developer for a driven company and to add value across a range of projects, instilling good practices and improving the knowledge and understanding of junior team members along the way.

Experience

Cambridge Assessment / Web UI Developer

MARCH 2018 - PRESENT

Having spent many years working for marketing and digital agencies, seeking a change of environment, I joined Cambridge Assessment as a member of their Agile development team.

Key accomplishments:

- Led the development of the Content Banking UI application, from making technical decisions, working closely with the UX team and developing the UI through to writing and maintaining the test suite using React Testing Library and Jest
- Selected to join the newly-formed Customer & Technology team and developed the UI for CPSQ application, including the creation of an AuthO single sign-on service, React front-ends for multiple connected services and a test suite involving Cypress, Jest and Enzyme
- Developed and maintained the UI for the Transcription Processing application, using barcode scanning and video streaming via a Raspberry Pi for image capturing
- Ported the Xopus-based XML editor for CCMS' Authoring component over to Froala

 Joined the BTS team and developed the UI for the new CCMS application, converting the legacy product's existing functionality into a fresh, reimagined Angular-based implementation

BBD Perfect Storm / Front-end Web Developer

MARCH 2017 - MARCH 2018

I joined BBD Perfect Storm's highly skilled and super-creative digital team in a more senior role, and enjoyed working on a number of exciting projects using Angular, Redux and Laravel.

Key accomplishments:

- Built Investec's Culture Roadshow internal website using GSAP's TweenMax library
- Built the London Fire Brigade's Fire Fighting Careers website with custom WordPress Advanced Custom Fields integration
- Built and maintained the admin application for LIZH's Genie Facebook Messenger chatbot
- Maintained various assessment tools for Vitality
- Maintained Bridgestone's Dream Submission competition form and associated emails for their No Matter What microsite
- Built Vitality's green incentive email campaign and accompanying microsite

Morse Digital / Front-end Web Developer

APRIL 2014 - FEBRUARY 2017

As part of the core Front-end team, my responsibilities included building, testing and maintaining the front-end code base, developing prototypes, advising designers on potential build caveats, meeting with clients and deploying production-ready code.

Key accomplishments:

- Provided design consultancy, build, maintenance and i18n internationalisation for the re-launch of GLL's Better website
- Designed and built the London Sport Funding Search Tool website

- Built and maintained GLL's London Aquatics Centre and Copper Box Arena websites, and later converted them into responsive builds
- Provided design consultancy and build for the Sony Pictures UK and Tabasco Best of the Brunch Tumblr blogs
- Wrote a number of vanilla JavaScript modules which are in use across many of Morse's websites

Spinnaker London / Front-end Web Developer

AUGUST 2013 - MARCH 2014

Key accomplishments:

- Provided design consultancy and build for the re-launch of the Walkabout website
- Refactored Baking Mad's recipe section to include microdata for SEO
- Provided design consultancy and build for the re-launch of IMEX's email campaigns

Spinnaker London / Junior Front-end Web Developer

JANUARY 2012 - JULY 2013, LONDON

I worked alongside Spinnaker's inspirational Creative and Technical team to deliver some fantastic results across a number of platforms, from HTML emails to websites, microsites, Facebook campaigns and Rich Media advertising.

Key accomplishments:

- Built and maintained HTML email campaigns for Baking Mad, Bord Bia, IMEX, Patak's and Tabasco
- Provided regular maintenance on the Baking Mad website
- Refactored the Less stylesheets on the Blue Dragon website

Skills

- Broad knowledge of JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Angular, CSS and semantic HTML
- Experience with Enzyme, React Testing Library, Jest, Jasmine, Cucumber, SonarQube and Azure pipelines
- A firm understanding of typography and graphic design principles in application to front-end development
- Awareness of usability, accessibility, cross-browser testing and responsive design issues
- Experience with Ruby on Rails
- Experience with Laravel
- Experience with MySQL and other relational databases
- Knowledge of Adobe Photoshop

Education

The Open University / Certificate in Web Applications Development

2008 - 2010